让我们想象一下，我们有一个机器人，我们想要根据它来定位它的抓手
Let’s imagine we have a robot and we want to position its gripper with respect to this
紫色三角形，想象一下我们想把夹子直接放在中心上方
purple triangle and imagine that we want to have the gripper directly above the centre
三角形和高度这样的东西。
of the triangle and at a height something like this.
因此，如果我们在机器人的抓手上有一个摄像头，它会看到类似这样的视图。在
So if we had a camera on the robot’s gripper, it would see a view something like this. In
机器人从这里看到的特殊视图，抓手的姿势
the particular view that the robot is seeing from here, the pose of the gripper with respect
对象是隐含的。例如，如果机器人抓手最初处于某个位置
to the object is implicit. For instance, if the robot gripper was initially in a position
像这样，我们可以看到相机获取的图像是完全不同的。所以，如果我们
like this, we can see that the image acquired by the camera is quite different. So if we
可以想出一个控制算法，将视图从此更改为此
could come up with a control algorithm that would change the view from this to this, then
隐含地，机器人将在世界坐标系中执行期望的运动。
implicitly the robot is going to perform the desired motion in the world coordinate frame.
这是我们刚刚讨论过的问题的图形表示。我们有
Here’s a graphical representation of the problem that we just discussed. We have the
对象的初始视图。在这种情况下，我们的对象是一个三角形，它的定义很明确
initial view of the object. In this case, our object is a triangle and it’s well-defined
通过其三个角的坐标。这是对象最初的样子。但
by the coordinates of its three corners. This is what the object looks like initially. But
我希望三角形在我的图像中看起来像这样。
I want the triangle to look like this in my image.
它的三个角的坐标也很明确。所以我们可以定义我们的
It’s also well-defined by the coordinates of its three corners. So we can define our
将对象的视图从此更改为此问题。我们想做的是
problem as changing the view of the object from this to this. What we want to do is to
将黄色圆圈移动到红色圆圈所在的位置。像这样。
move the yellow circles to where the red circles are. Just like this.
为了移动，这些黄色圆圈需要有一定的速度。他们需要有一个
In order to move, these yellow circles need to have some velocity. They need to have a
速度朝向相应的红色圆圈。所以这里是一个黄色的坐标
velocity towards the corresponding red circle. So here is the coordinate of one of the yellow
圆圈，这是它的速度。它需要具有这种速度，这将成为它
circles and here is its velocity. It needs to have this velocity, which would make it
从它所在的地方移动到它需要去的地方。
move from where it is to where it needs to go.
我们已经讨论了像素速度和相机速度之间的关系。它的
We’ve already discussed a relationship between pixel velocity and camera velocity. It’s
由雅可比矩阵图像给出。我们可以将矩阵编写为函数。我叫它
given by the image Jacobian Matrix. We can write the matrix as a function. I call it
Jp和它代表Jacobian的点特征，它是像素的函数
Jp and that stands for Jacobian for a point feature and it’s a function of the pixel
坐标，u和v，这个点在世界上的距离是多少，由资本Z给出。
coordinate, u and v, also how far the point is away in the world, which is given by capital Z.
我们称之为深度。对于三点，请记住我们有一点
We refer to that as the depth of the point. For three points, remember we have a point
在三角形的每个角上，我们可以描述我们想要点一的速度，
on each corner of the triangle, we can describe the velocity that we want point one to have,
点二有三点就有了。我们所做的只是堆叠三个
point two to have and point three to have. All that we’re doing is just stacking three
方程组，一个在另一个之上，并作为公共因子，即相机速度。
sets of equations, one above the other and as a common factor, which is the camera velocity.
在中间，我们有一堆这些图像雅各比人。所以对于三点，关系
In the middle, we have a stack of these image Jacobians. So for three points, the relationship
在像素速度，相机速度之间，看起来像这样。这个中间矩阵，堆栈
between the pixel velocities, camera velocity, looks like this. This middle matrix, the stack
图像雅可比人，现在是六乘六矩阵。
of image Jacobians, is now a six by six matrix.
他们每个人都是二乘六。将它们中的三个堆叠在一起。结果是
Each of them is two by six. Stack three of them on top of each other. The result is a
六乘六矩阵。因为这个矩阵是方形的，我们可以反转它。我们有一段感情
six by six matrix. Because this matrix is square, we can invert it. We have a relationship
看起来像这样。这是所需的相机速度。如果相机移动了
that looks like this. This is the desired camera velocity. If the camera moved like
这样，所有点都将具有所需的像素速度。他们会从哪里搬家
this, then all the points would have the desired pixel velocity. They would move from where
它们是黄色圆圈所示，表示您希望它们用红色圆圈表示的位置。
they are, shown by the yellow circle, to where you want them to be indicated by the red circle.
所以这是我们想要的速度和相机的速度之间的关系
So this is a relationship between the velocity that we want and the velocity that the camera
需要具有以使图像中的更改看起来像这样。这是计算出来的
needs to have in order to make the change in the image look like this. It’s computed
通过图像雅可比矩阵的逆序。
via the inverse of the stack of image Jacobian matrices.
现在让我们看看如何计算所需的像素速度。我们要介绍一下
Let’s look now at how we might compute the desired pixel velocity. We’re going to introduce
一些额外的符号。我将使用星号或星号来表示所需的值
some extra notation. I’m going to use the asterisk or star to indicate the desired value
一定数量。所以我们想要的像素是由U*和V*表示的
of a quantity. So where we want the pixel to be is indicated by U* and V* and where
它当前是，由坐标U，V表示。所以如果我只是区分它们
it currently is, is indicated by the coordinate U, V. So if I simply take the difference between
我希望它在哪里以及它现在在哪里，并以任意比例乘以它
where I want it to be and where it is now and multiply that by some arbitrary scale
因子lambda，我有一个方程，它描述了所需的像素速度。
factor lambda, I have an equation, which describes the desired pixel velocity.
它是一个平行于我所在位置和我想要位置之间的线的向量。我用
It’s a vector parallel to a line between where I am and where I want to be. I use the
下标“我”，因为这是我们可以应用于任何一个的一般关系
subscript “I” because this is a general relationship that we can apply to any of the
我们对象的角点。在这种情况下，它是一个三角形物体，所以“我”变化
corner points of our object. In this case, it’s a triangular object so “I” varies
从一到三。
from one to three.
我介绍一点符号。我用符号“P”表示矢量
I introduce a bit more notation. I use the symbol “P” which is a vector to represent
一个点的坐标，并将其替换为先前的关系，现在我
the coordinate of a point and substituting that into the previous relationship, now I
有一个表达式告诉我相机所需的速度，如此所示
have an expression that tells me the desired velocity of the camera as indicated by this
star下标等于lambda，一个任意游戏，乘以堆栈的倒数
star subscript is equal to lambda, an arbitrary game, multiplied by the inverse of the stack
图像雅可比人，乘以另一个矢量，由另一个矢量组成
of image Jacobians, multiplied by another vector which is made up of a difference between
重点在哪里以及我想要的地方。
where the point is and where I’d like the point to be.
我们来看看这个的模拟。在左边，我们有一个模拟的图像平面。
Let’s have a look at a simulation of this. On the left, we have a simulated image plane.
因此，圆圈表示当前投影对象的位置，星号表示
So the circles indicate where the object is currently projected and the asterisks indicate
在哪里，我希望这些点被投射到。星号是
where it is that I would like those points to be projected to. The asterisks are the
目的地坐标。在右侧，我们可以看到正在发生的事情
destination coordinates. On the right hand side, we have a 3D view of what’s going
上。三个红色球体表示三维空间中的点，即角落
on. The three red spheres indicate the points in three-dimensional space, the corners of
三角形。在蓝色中，我们有一个附加的相机的简单3D表示
the triangle. In blue, we have a simple 3D representation of a camera with an attached
相机坐标框架。
camera coordinate frame.
当我开始模拟时，我们可以看到相机正朝着三个点移动
When I start the simulation, we can see that the camera is moving towards the three points
在世界上，最初它移动很快，然后放慢速度。
in the world and initially it moves quite quickly and then slows down.
这是我们使用的比例控制器的一个特征
This is a characteristic of the proportional controller that we’re using demonstrates
渐近收敛，我们可以看到圆圈，那些世界的当前观点
asymptotic convergence and we can see that the circles, the current view of those world
图像平面上的点移动缓慢但肯定朝着期望的目标移动。
points on the image plane moving slowly but surely towards the desired goals.
发生的事情是简单地指定在图像平面上需要发生的事情
What’s happened is by simply specifying what needs to happen on the image plane that
这个坐标需要移动到这个坐标，在现实世界中，在三维中
this coordinate needs to move to this coordinate, in the real world, in the three-dimensional
世界，任务已经完成。相机已移动到所需的姿势。
world, the task has been completed. The camera has moved to a desired pose.
但是在实现这一任务时，我们没有必要说出任何关于姿势的事情
But notice in achieving that task, we haven’t had to say anything about the pose of the
相机或现实世界中物体的姿势。整个任务已经完成
camera or the pose of the objects in the real world. This whole task has been completed
只需将图像平面上的误差驱动为零即可。
simply by driving to zero the error on the image plane.
这是我们所谓的基于图像的视觉伺服的重要特征。
This is an important characteristic of what we call image-based visual servoing.
我们来看一个具体的例子。这是我初始化的MATLAB工作区
Let’s look at a concrete example here. This is my MATLAB workspace which I've initialized
有一些变数。
with a few variables.
我用我们以前见过的默认设置创建了一个相机对象。我已定义了
I've created a camera object with the default settings we've seen before. I've defined the
世界坐标中三角形的顶点，它们由列的代表
vertices of a triangle in world coordinates and they’re represented by the columns of
矩阵“P”和我创造了一个均匀的变换，代表了姿势
the matrix “P” and I have created a homogeneous transformation which represents the pose of
世界空间内的摄像机，我通过定义位置和旋转来完成
the camera within the world space and I've done that by defining a position and rotation
在这里通过这种均匀变换给出的X，Y和Z轴周围。
around the X, Y and Z axes given by this homogeneous transformation here.
因此，我可以使用绘图将世界点的投影绘制到图像平面上
So I can plot the projection of the world points on to the image plane, using the plot
相机对象的方法，传递三个世界点的坐标，
method of the camera object, pass in the coordinates of the three world points, the
矩阵P的列和我将告诉对象相机姿势处于
columns of the matrix P and I’m going to tell the object that the camera pose is at
这个变量在这里，T-cam。现在我们看到这三个点在图像上的投影
this variable here, T-cam. Now we see the projection of those three points on the image
平面。我们可以看到相机离三角形有一段距离了
plane. We can see that the camera is some distance away from the triangle and it’s
有点倾斜地看着三角形。
looking at the triangle somewhat obliquely.
绘图方法返回了图像平面上的投影，并由它们给出
The plot method has returned the projections on the image plane and they’re given by
矩阵的列很少b。现在我可以用这三个来计算雅可比图像
the columns of the matrix little b. Now I can compute an image Jacobian from these three
点。我通过再次使用visjac_p方法，视觉雅可比行为点特征来做到这一点
points. I do that by again using the visjac_p method, visual Jacobian for point features
而且我要传递点特征，小p，这包含三点和
and I’m going to pass in the point features, little p and this contains three points and
我要指出所有的点都距离相机5米。
I’m going to specify that all the points are five meters away from the camera.
这不是严格意义上的。我实际上并不知道这些点有多远，但对于
This is not strictly true. I don’t actually know how far away the points are but for the
那个时刻和我在一起，我们只会把它放在第五位。
moment bare with me and we’ll just put in the number five.
现在我们为三个点中的每个点都有视觉雅可比。每个点都有两个
Now we have the visual Jacobian’s for each of the three points. Each point has a two
通过六个图像雅可比行列式，现在它们都被堆叠起来，结果是六乘六矩阵
by six image Jacobian and now they’re all stacked up so the result is a six by six matrix
在工作区中。这是我可以反转的矩阵。这是一个方阵。如果我
in the workspace. This is a matrix that I could invert. It’s a square matrix. If I
使用此矩阵乘以所需图像平面速度的矢量，结果将是
use this matrix to multiply a vector of desired image plane velocities, the result will be
相机为实现这一目标所需的空间速度。
the spatial velocity that the camera needs in order to achieve that.
总而言之，基于图像的视觉伺服就是用来描述任务
So in summary, image-based visual servoing is all about describing a task in terms of
我们希望点如何在图像中移动。然后我们构造一个移动的简单控制器
how we want points to move in the image. We then construct a simple controller that moves
相机，以创建我们需要的点运动。
the camera so as to create the point motion that we require.
随着这些点从现在的位置移动到我们想要的位置，这是有用的
As the points move from where they are now to where we’d like them to be, the useful
任务是在3D世界中实现的。但是这个任务没有用姿势来描述
task is achieved in the 3D world. But the task is not described in terms of pose of
物体或机器人。事实上，任务隐含在我们在图像平面上所需的运动中。
objects or of the robot. The task is in fact implicit in the motion that we require on the image plane.
在某些方面，我们谈论的是相机的相对运动。我们正在指导
In some ways, we’re talking about relative motion of the camera. We’re steering the
相机朝向目标位置。它没有用绝对值来定义。我们没有
camera towards the goal location. It’s not defined in terms of absolutes. We don’t
需要知道相机的姿势或物体相对于任何类型的姿势
need to know the pose of the camera or the pose of the objects with respect to any kind
世界坐标系。
of world coordinate frame.
这种技术在我们得到三分的特殊情况下非常有效
This technique works really well in this particular case where we have got three points in the
现场。它不仅仅适用于一两点，而且在一个案例中要复杂得多
scene. It doesn't work for just one or two points and it’s much more complex in a case
我们有四个或更多点。
where we have four or more points.
这肯定是可行的，但有点复杂，超出了这个特定讲座的范围。
It’s certainly doable but a little more complicated and beyond the scope of this particular lecture.